There's a crazy new machine on this new
telescope, and it could one day help us
find aliens. The big problem with
finding aliens right now is that it's
hard to see Earth-like planets because
there's too much glare from the bright
stars that they orbit. So, one way to
fix this is to physically block the
star's light with a disc, kind of like
sticking your thumb up to cover the sun
from your eyes. But, this telescope uses
a new technique. It has circular masks
to block the brightest part of the glare
in the same way that a sun visor in your
car blocks the brightest parts of the
sun. But, light can still bend and spill
around the corners. So, to get rid of
that leaky starlight, special mirrors
that change shape using hundreds of
little pistons and a combination of
patterned discs and light blockers that
bend the star's light so that it cancels
itself out, like the two opposite waves
in this Slinky. So, it dims that
blindingly bright starlight and lets the
faint light from a planet shine through.
And then, powerful software enhances the
image even more, making this instrument
100 to 1,000 times more powerful than
any other of its kind on a space
telescope ever, showing us brand new
planets. To see what it finds,
subscribe.